Nielsen, Waldo J. Collection of Utility Workers Organization in New York Materials 5049
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Waldo J. Nielsen Collection of Utility Workers Organization in New York Materials
1934-1976
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Nielsen, Waldo J.
5049
0.33 cubic feet
0.3 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Newsletters and other periodical publications of Utility workers' unions, most in New York State.
5975951
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 06, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5493: Elmer E. Hilpert Arbitration Papers
Arbitration, Industrial; Public utilities -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Public utilities -- United States -- Employees; Cole, David Lawrence, 1902-1977.; Wallen, Saul, 1910-1969; Whiting, Dudley E.; Flight Engineers' International Association; Trans World Airlines; United States. Emergency Board No. 123; Utility Workers Union of America; Powermen; Utility Worker News; Utility Workers Bulletin; Utility Post; Brotherhood Record; Edison Equity News; Utility Worker News; Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc.; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers; Brooklyn Union Gas Company; Edison Electric Light Company; Edison Electric Light Company. Equity Local 100; Edison Electric Light Company. Brooklyn Local 102; Edison Electric Light Company. Queens Local 103
5975951
- Powdermen, 1934-1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  (Utility Employees) April and July 1934
- Edison Equity News, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  (Equity Local 100, Utility Employees) No. 3,4 1935; No. 2,3,4,6 1934
- Utility Workers News, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  (Locals 100,102,103 Utility Workers.) No. 1, 1935 (Special Issue)
- Utility Workers Bulletin, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  (NY Regional Board of Brotherhood of Utility Workers.) No. 2, 1936
- Utility Post (Independent Gas and Electric Union), 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  v.1:no.1-9 (1938); v.2:no.1, 3 (1939); v.3:no.3 (1940)
- Brotherhood Record (Brotherhood of Consolidated Edison Employees), 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  v.1:no.1 (1940)
- Metropolitan Club Retired Employees. Consolidated Edison of New York (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Newsletters and miscellaneous, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "My Experiences in Unionism in the Utility Industry" by Jens P. Nielson (Box 1, Folder 9)
  By J. P. Nielsen 22p.
- Broadsides Local 1-2 Utility Workers (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence with Fred Javitz and other (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Regarding retirement program at Con Edison
- News clippings, 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Other correspondence, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Regarding independent gas and electric union affiliating with Utility Workers.